Andrea Wesley Ciardi

Senior Frontend Developer

Contact

Address

Marousi, Athens, 15124

Phone

+30 6945051674

E-mail

developer@andreaciardi.co m

LinkedIn

Andrea Wesley Ciardi

Skills

HTML 5

Excellent

Css3

Excellent

Sass

Very Good

Less

Very Good

Javascript / JQuery

Very Good

React

Very Good

AngularJS

Excellent

Born in Sao Paulo, Brasil.

Grew up in Milan, Italy.

Based in Athens, Greece.

Almost a decade and half of professional work in Web Development. Passionate and focused on keep up with the evolution of web technologies.

Start to work in early age gave me the advantage of "built up" knowledge about the foundations of web languages like HTML, Javascript and Css that still to these days are the core of every modern framework. Knowing the core of frontend languages my learning curve proves to be very fast keeping me constantly updated and relevant in the market.

Work History

2016-05 -Current

Senior Frontend Developer

OSeven Telematics, Halandri, Athens

- OSeven Telematics is a B2B, product oriented, Insurtech company.
- As Senior Frontend Developer I was tasked with develop a fully responsive and cross browsing compatible web portal that consumes Google and custom APIs. Because of the high interactivity with the user great focus was given to UI and UX.
- From January 2020: following Scrum methodology and using Teams, Jira and Git, leaded a team with juniors Frontend and Backend developers and one QA tester.
- From July 2019: Refactored completely and further developed OSeven's UBI web portal replacing old technologies with ReactJS, Typescript, Sass, ReactBootstrap, WebPack and Yarn.
- From May 2016 to June 2019: Developed OSeven's UBI Web-portal using AngularJS, Html5, Less, Bootstrap3, Grunt, Coffee and NPM.

2016-02 -2016-04

Frontend Developer

SpotMechanic, Nea Ionia, Athens

 SpotMechanic provides to private buyers, technical and analytical inspection on used cars before to process them.



- Created a fully working demo, translating directly the brainstormed ideas of the CEO to technical requirements.
- Developed a "mobile first" demo Web-app using AngularJS, Less, Bootstrap 3, custom Rest APIs, Grunt and NPM. Organized tasks and code with Trello and Git.

2015-07 -**Frontend Developer** 2015-12

Wide Side, Milan

- For " CheBanca! ": as part of a large and internationally based team of Frontend Developers I was tasked with develop a fully responsive and cross browsing compatible, "mobile first", Web-portal for the new e-banking service. Because of the high sensibility of the data, the main focus was put into apply all best practice and standards related to cyber-security.
- Developed with AngularJS, I took on me as main task to restructure all the code for make possible the upgrade from the basic "built-in" single layer routing of AngularJS to the multilayer ngRouting, with the scope to unblock the full potential of the framework.

2015-03 -Frontend Developer 2015-06

CGM Consulting, Milan

- For "Credito Emiliano": as part of a small team of Frontend developers I was tasked with develop a fully responsive and cross browsing compatible, "mobile first", Web-portal for the new e-banking service. Because of the high sensibility of the data, the main focus was put into apply all best practice and standards related to cyber-security.
- Developed with AngularJS, Less, Bootstrap 3, custom Rest APIs, Grunt and NPM.
- I joined the team in the final steps of the project. Working in a stressful environment due to the short deadlines, I helped successfully to not to miss the final release date.

2014-12 -**Full Stack Developer**

2015-04

Zero2032, Milan

 Designed and implemented website for new business, collecting ideas and feedbacks directly

- from the founding members.
- Utilizing interactive forms the website offers the possibility to users to request and book appointments for dental care services.
- Used MySQL database, PHP for build custom APIs and AngularJS, Less, Bootstrap 3, Grunt and NPM for Frontend.
- Because the website needed to be highly ranked in Google searches, "dynamic rendering" has been implemented using Prerender.io.

2014-07 -2015-02

Frontend Developer

One4, Milan

- For "Acemill": As part of a small team, developed a website for advertise the annual economical convention in Milan. Developed using Liferay, HTML 5, Jquery, Css3. https://www.salonedelrisparmio.com/
- For "Beta80": As part of a small team, developed a social network for the participants of an annual business convention. The scope was to create contacts between the participants, before the physical meeting at the convention. Developed using AngularJS, Less, Bootstrap 3, custom Rest APIs, Grunt and NPM.
- For "Monte dei Paschi di Siena": As part of a large team, developed a fully responsive and cross browsing compatible Web-portal for the new e-banking service. I joined the team in the final steps of the project. My task and complete focus was into adjust the style of the pages reproducing the mockups at "pixel-perfect" level. Almost entirely developed using Css3.

2014-02 -2014-07

Frontend Developer

Modis, Milan

- For "Nexus Advanced Technologies srl": As part of a small team, developed a portal for cars monitoring system.
- Used JavascriptMVC framework, Html5, Less, Bootstrap3 and Google APIs.

2013-02 -2014-01

Frontend Developer

Avanade Italia, Milan

• For " Cariparma ": As part of a small team,

- developed the company public website https://conti.credit-agricole.it/. Used Sharepoint, ASP.Net, C#, Html5, Css3, Ajax and JQuery.
- For "ABB": As part of a small team, developed the company public website https://new.abb.com/it. Used JavascriptMVC framework, Html, Css, Bootstrap 2, Ajax and JQuery.
- For "DeAgostini": As part of a small team, developed the company public website https://www.deagostini.com/it/. Used Silverlight, Html, Css.

2013-10 -2013-12

Full Stack Developer

Spazio IRIS, Milan

- Designed and implemented the website http://www.spazioiris.it, collecting ideas and feedbacks directly from the founding members.
- Utilizing interactive forms the website offers the possibility to users to book the participation at seminars and private meetings with psychologist.
- Used Access database, ASP.Net and VB.Net 4.0 for build custom APIs, and JavascriptMVC framework, Css, Bootstrap 2 and Grunt for Frontend.

2013-05 -2013-08

Full Stack Developer

Capoeira Sou Eu, Milan

- Designed and implemented the website http://www.capoeirasoueu.it for sport association, collecting ideas and feedbacks directly from the owner.
- Used Access database, ASP.Net and VB.Net 4.0 for build custom APIs, and JavascriptMVC framework, Css, Bootstrap 2 and Grunt for Frontend.

2013-01 -2013-02

Full Stack Developer

Spazio Baiard, Sondrio

- Designed and implemented the website http://www.baiard.it for yoga association, collecting ideas and feedbacks directly from the owner.
- Used Access database, ASP.Net and VB.Net 4.0 for build custom APIs, and JQuery, Css, Bootstrap

2 and Grunt for Frontend.

2012-11 -2013-02

Web Designer

Team Consultance, Milan

- For "HP / Fastweb S.p.A. Italia": Researched and edited photos for the articles presented in the daily online newspaper. Edited images for advertisements.
- Used Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator.

2012-10 -2012-12

Full Stack Developer

Loja Brasil, Milan

- Designed and implemented the website http://www.lojabrasil.it for physical shop of Brazilian products, collecting ideas and feedbacks directly from the owner.
- Used MySQL database, PHP for customize APIs, and the CMS PrestaShop.com, and Css for Frontend.

2011-11 -2012-10

Frontend Developer

Accenture Italia, Milan

- For "Philip Morris International": As part of a small team, developed e-learning portal. Used Flash and Articulate Storyline.
- For "Fiat Group Automobiles S.p.A.": As part of a large team, developed the company public website https://www.fiat.it/. Used Html, Css, Ajax and JQuery.
- For "Ducati Motor Holding S.p.A.": As part of a small team, developed a functional prototype for the new mobile application of the company.
 Used Html, Css, Ajax, JQuery and JQuery Mobile.
- For "MediaShopping S.p.A.": As part of a small team, developed the company public website https://www.mediashopping.it/. Used Html, Css and JQuery.
- For "Danone S.p.A.": As part of a small team, developed the company public website https://www.vividanone.it/. Used Html, Css, Javascript and Liferay.
- For "Vodafone Italia": As part of a small team, developed a functional prototype for the new mobile application of the company. Used Html, Css, Ajax, JQuery and JQuery Mobile.

2009-10 -2011-10

Software Developer

Gruppo Sicis, Milan, Brescia

- For "Mf Honyvem": As part of a large team, developed management software for financial marketing company. Used Access, SqlServer and AS400 databases, VB6, ASP, Html, Css and Javascript.
- For "Class Editore": As part of a small team, developed management software for forecast tv channel. Used Oracle database, C#, ASP.Net, Html, XML, Css, Ajax and Javascript.
- For "Elsevier Srl": As part of a small team, developed management software for pharmaceutical company. Used Oracle database, ASP, Html, XML, Css, Ajax and Javascript.

2011-04 -2011-09

Software Developer

JetPark, Milan

- Developed management software for airport parking company.
- Used Oracle and MySql databases, VB.Net, PHP, Asp.Net, Html, Css and Javascript.

2009-06 -2009-10

Help Desk Technician and Database Manager

TUV Rheinland Italia S.p.A., Pogliano Milanese

- Help desk of first level operating on HP machines with Windows OS.
- Build and managed company database. Used Lotus Notes database.

2008-09 -2009-06

Software Developer

Team Netuse, Garbagnate Milanese

 Participating to a Staging program, attended technical lessons and developed generic management software. Used Access and SqlServer databases, VB.Net, VB6, ASP, Html, Css and Javascript.

2008-07 -2008-09

Help Desk Technician

Emc2, Lainate

 For "OM Carrelli Elevatori": Help desk of first level operating on various machines with Windows OS.

Education

2003-09 -2008-06

High School Diploma

Stanislao Cannizzaro - Rho, Milan, Italy

Hobbies

My hobbies are: Technologies, Physical training, Skateboarding, Capoeira (Brazilian martial art) and Woodworking.

What I've learned from them...

Technologies: the world will keep turning without wait you. Is on you to keep the pace.

Physical training: when you commit to something there is not space for procrastination.

Skateboarding: is not enough to look others for learn to do something. Proactiveness and perseverance are "must have".

Capoeira: when you are part of a team everything you do affects also others. There is no shame in ask for help.

Woodworking: the quality of what you make is directly proportionate to the effort and focus you put in it.